<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Blog &#8211; Libral India</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:53:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/cropped-logo-search-grid-1x-removebg-preview-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Blog &#8211; Libral India</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Would you like your history slanderous or boring?</title>
		<link>/would-you-like-your-history-slanderous-or-boring/</link>
					<comments>/would-you-like-your-history-slanderous-or-boring/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 08:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/would-you-like-your-history-slanderous-or-boring/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[by guest contributor Caio Ferreira “A journal, sir, is no more a history than materials are a house.” Voltaire wrote this to the historian Jöran Andersson Nordberg,... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><em>by guest contributor <em>Caio Ferreira</em></em></p>
<p>“A journal, sir, is no more a history than materials are a house.” Voltaire wrote this to the historian Jöran Andersson Nordberg, chaplain of king Charles XII of Sweden, in 1744. They respond assertively to a series of criticisms Voltaire received from Nordberg two years prior concerning his <a href="http://gallica.bnf.fr/ark:/12148/bpt6k37531x"><em>Histoire de Charles XII</em></a>. In his own account of Charles XII’s reign (<a href="http://reader.digitale-sammlungen.de/de/fs1/object/display/bsb10619364_00011.html"><em>Konung Carl XII:s historia</em></a>, 1740), Nordberg dedicated an entire introduction to correcting the liberties that previous historians had taken with the source material. One of his main targets had been none other than Voltaire himself.</p>
<p><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="193" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/02/02/would-you-like-your-history-slanderous-or-boring/charles-xii-nordberg/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/charles-xii-nordberg.jpg?fit=3125%2C4071&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3125,4071" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Charles XII Nordberg" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/charles-xii-nordberg.jpg?fit=230%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/charles-xii-nordberg.jpg?fit=580%2C756&amp;ssl=1" class="aligncenter wp-image-193 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524154_614_charles-xii-nordberg.jpg" alt="Charles XII Nordberg" width="580" height="756" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript>What remains interesting is the debate that sprang from Nordberg’s criticism. If, on the one hand, the chapelain admitted that Voltaire’s “beauty and vivacity of style” was commendable, his final verdict was nevertheless severe: <em>Histoire de Charles XII</em>, with its alarming lack of reliable sources, disseminated a number of imprecisions about the reign of the Swedish king. Quoting from <a href="http://gallica.bnf.fr/ark:/12148/bpt6k71749x"><em>La Voltairomanie </em></a>(a critical essay on Voltaire published by Pierre-François Guyot Desfontaines in 1740), Nordberg suggested that Voltaire’s book was not historiography at all but a “historical novel.” As such, it was unworthy of being read.</p>
<p>Voltaire concedes to all those criticisms. In his response, he does not try to defend his sources or his research methods. Instead, Voltaire shifted the conversation entirely. To him, the sloppiness of the work was excusable to the degree that it affected “insignificant truths” (e.g. the location of the chapel in Charles XII’s castle and the precise minutia of his regalia). What Voltaire “got wrong” were mere trivialities bearing little or no importance to his larger narrative. As a historian, Voltaire was surely committed to telling the truth, <a href="http://www.columbia.edu/~pf3/voltaire.pdf">but the truth he aimed for proved more specific in his mind</a>. Such a history was not meant to be all-encompassing, but rather to preserve what as “worthy of being transmitted to posterity.”</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="194" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/02/02/would-you-like-your-history-slanderous-or-boring/histoire-charles-xii-voltaire/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/histoire-charles-xii-voltaire.jpg?fit=1024%2C1482&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,1482" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Histoire Charles XII Voltaire" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/histoire-charles-xii-voltaire.jpg?fit=207%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/histoire-charles-xii-voltaire.jpg?fit=580%2C839&amp;ssl=1" class="aligncenter wp-image-194 size-large jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Histoire Charles XII Voltaire" width="580" height="839" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/histoire-charles-xii-voltaire.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="194" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/02/02/would-you-like-your-history-slanderous-or-boring/histoire-charles-xii-voltaire/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/histoire-charles-xii-voltaire.jpg?fit=1024%2C1482&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,1482" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Histoire Charles XII Voltaire" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/histoire-charles-xii-voltaire.jpg?fit=207%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/histoire-charles-xii-voltaire.jpg?fit=580%2C839&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-194 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524156_823_histoire-charles-xii-voltaire.jpg" alt="Histoire Charles XII Voltaire" width="580" height="839" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></p>
<p>At the same time, Voltaire also had a distinct yet equally important goal: presenting an engaging narrative. It was important to produce a history in the mold of Tacitus and Livy, one that avoided “particularizing petty facts” and “preparing colors” in order to focus on “painting the picture.” To illustrate this, the <em>philosophe </em>punctuated his letter with an infamous quip: “A historian has many duties. Allow me to remind you here of two which are of some importance. The first is not to slander; the second is not to bore. I can excuse you for neglecting the first because few will read your work; I cannot, however, forgive you for neglecting the second, for I was forced to read you.” To this end, Voltaire accepted a certain “sloppiness.”</p>
<p>Reading this exchange now gives rise to conflicting emotions. On the one hand, it’s not difficult to side with Voltaire—not only because of his piercing rhetoric, but because no scholar wants to go unread. On the other hand, Nordberg’s complaints sound eerily contemporary. Despite his overzealousness, Nordberg represents current academic concerns and scholarly paradigms. His professional ethos seems alive and well: the first duty of the historian is to be as precise as possible, with entertainment being a welcome but unnecessary addition.</p>
<p>What remains curious is that history’s potential to delight and entertain long appeared to be its defining characteristic. The origins of this perspective presumably travel as far back to Cicero. He established that the historian was tasked not only with revealing the truth, but with revealing it in its entirety. However, Cicero also assumed that the intrinsic connection between history and oratory went much deeper than the mere recording of facts in chronological order. A good way to visualize this is to consider Cicero’s differentiation between annals and historiography: the former remains a simple registry, while the latter transforms into a registry “given distinction” through rules of speech. If truth was a concern, so was the ability of the historian to elevate certain facts above others, to give them emotional weight through the use of linguistic and narrative techniques.</p>
<p>The very notion of exemplarity (or even the larger idea of a <em>Historia magistra vitae</em>) carries within it the germ of this concern. <a href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/2504234?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents">Even before Cicero, Roman rhetoricians already supposed that the vividness of examples had a positive impact on moral education</a>. Such authors as Polybius seemed to understand that virtue might be better taught through narrative presentation than through demanding metaphysical inquiry. The life of Alexander the Great demonstrated “courage” better than any conceptual investigation. Early modern humanism certainly proved keen on this idea. Even Sir Philip Sidney—who otherwise thought of historiography as an inferior pedagogical tool compared to poetry—necessarily contended that its narrative aspect had a profound value. In all of these cases, an implicit agreement emerges so far as a valid historical account proves one that, while truthful, is also capable of embracing its ludic aspects. Pleasure was a constitutive and not simply a contingent part of historiography.</p>
<p>It seems, however, that when we reach Voltaire the tension between truth and pleasure has grown to be almost irreconcilable: the epistemological status of historical writing can no longer support the two principles. As early as 1566, Jean Bodin wrote that “I have made up my mind that it is practically an impossibility for the man who writes to give pleasure, to impart the truth of the matter also.” As such, we cannot say that Nordberg perspective was idiosyncratic, nor can we claim it did not count many adherents. Many nineteenth-century historians from Ranke to Langlois and Seignobos reaffirmed the commitment to truth as the only real interest of history.</p>
<p>Ultimately, I believe this debate is worth recuperating. It not only poses interesting questions—in particular, what were the epistemological shifts that facilitated this change?—but also serves as a locus point for history and literature considered together. Here, the questions of how historians view themselves, of <a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/195553/bonfire-humanities">how they define their own practices, goals, and the necessary compromises will </a><a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/195553/bonfire-humanities">continue to engage us all</a>.</p>
<p><em>Caio Ferreira is a first-year doctoral student in the Department of French and Romance Philology at Columbia University. He works on historiography and the intellectual history of early modern Europe.</em></p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/would-you-like-your-history-slanderous-or-boring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When did Amish become Old-Fashioned?</title>
		<link>/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/</link>
					<comments>/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 08:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[by guest contributor Ben Goossen By now the tropes are well worn: buggies, bonnets, and broad brimmed hats. Although Anabaptists around the world are incredibly diverse, ranging... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><em>by guest contributor Ben Goossen</em></p>
<p>By now the tropes are well worn: buggies, bonnets, and broad brimmed hats. Although Anabaptists around the world are incredibly diverse, ranging like many faith communities from ultraconservative to liberal-radical, popular stereotypes have long presented members as agrarian anti-modernists. Traditionalist Anabaptists, especially <a href="http://www.upne.com/9413668.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amish</a> and <a href="http://www.psupress.org/books/titles/0-271-02865-3.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Old Order Mennonites</a> who avoid cars and many forms of electricity, have come to be seen as a people temporally out of joint, time capsules of a past era. But which epoch might that be, exactly? And just how long have such notions been around?</p>
<figure id="attachment_771" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-771" style="width: 620px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/i.huffpost.com/gen/1988175/images/o-AMISH-HORSE-AND-BUGGY-facebook.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="771" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/29/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/horse-and-buggy/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/horse-and-buggy.jpg?fit=2000%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2000,1000" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Amish carriage&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;482572567&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Horse and Buggy" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;“Horse-and-buggy” Anabaptists like the Amish are often portrayed as relics of an earlier age (Huffington Post)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;“Horse-and-buggy” Anabaptists like the Amish are often portrayed as relics of an earlier age (Huffington Post)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/horse-and-buggy.jpg?fit=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/horse-and-buggy.jpg?fit=580%2C290&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-771 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524544_918_horse-and-buggy.jpg" alt="“Horse-and-buggy” Anabaptists like the Amish are often portrayed as relics of an earlier age (Huffington Post)" width="580" height="290" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-771" class="wp-caption-text">“Horse-and-buggy” Anabaptists like the Amish are often portrayed as relics of an earlier age (Huffington Post)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Conservative Anabaptists enjoy a distinctly positive reputation today. In a time of environmentalism, minimalism, and slow food movements, their agricultural orientation and emphasis on simplicity often seem appealing. But Amish tourism was not always an American pastime. As recently as a few decades ago, observers viewed traditionalists with hostility. Widespread faith in the wonders of satellites and microwaves led many to see them as ‘backward,’ a people that ‘<a href="https://jhupbooks.press.jhu.edu/content/amish" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">impeded progress for everyone</a>’ (x). According to midcentury theories of modernization, the world was on the up-and-up. So-called advanced countries like Great Britain and the United States were pushing the boundaries of progress, while places such as Southeast Asia and sub-Saharan Africa were still scrambling to catch up. This logic presented <a href="http://uncpress.unc.edu/books/T-1494.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">modern technology as a rubric</a> for measuring historical time. Like the allegedly underdeveloped countries of Cuba or Vietnam, Amish and Mennonites seemed trapped in the past.</p>
<figure id="attachment_772" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-772" style="width: 426px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://gameo.org/index.php?title=File:MWC-1967-Two-women-with-contrasting-dress.jpg&amp;filetimestamp=20130823171455" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img data-attachment-id="772" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/29/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/two-women/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/two-women.jpg?fit=426%2C503&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="426,503" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Two Women" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Mennonite women with different clothing styles at the 1967 Mennonite World Conference in Amsterdam (Mennonite Church USA Archives)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Mennonite women with different clothing styles at the 1967 Mennonite World Conference in Amsterdam (Mennonite Church USA Archives)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/two-women.jpg?fit=254%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/two-women.jpg?fit=426%2C503&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-772 size-full jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Mennonite women with different clothing styles at the 1967 Mennonite World Conference in Amsterdam (Mennonite Church USA Archives)" width="426" height="503" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/two-women.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="772" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/29/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/two-women/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/two-women.jpg?fit=426%2C503&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="426,503" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Two Women" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Mennonite women with different clothing styles at the 1967 Mennonite World Conference in Amsterdam (Mennonite Church USA Archives)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Mennonite women with different clothing styles at the 1967 Mennonite World Conference in Amsterdam (Mennonite Church USA Archives)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/two-women.jpg?fit=254%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/two-women.jpg?fit=426%2C503&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-772 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524545_309_two-women.jpg" alt="Mennonite women with different clothing styles at the 1967 Mennonite World Conference in Amsterdam (Mennonite Church USA Archives)" width="426" height="503" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-772" class="wp-caption-text">Mennonite women with different clothing styles at the 1967 Mennonite World Conference in Amsterdam (Mennonite Church USA Archives)</figcaption></figure>
<p>For those of us looking back from a position of postmodernity, modernization theory appears not a timeless law but the product of a specific historical moment. Hence while Anabaptist groups have long distinguished themselves from external populations, the idea that this was a rejection of ‘<a href="http://www.transactionpub.com/title/History-of-the-Idea-of-Progress-978-1-56000-713-5.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">progress</a>’ per se emerged only in recent years. Early modern Mennonites and Amish adopted <a href="http://www.brill.com/companion-anabaptism-and-spiritualism-1521-1700" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ascetic and iconoclastic theologies</a> not to resist the future, but as a means of distancing themselves from the corruptions of the ‘world.’ Until the twentieth century, their farming communities were often among the most likely to innovate, famously leading Max Weber to pronounce Anabaptists, “whose otherworldliness is as proverbial as their wealth,” the most outstanding bearers of the “<a href="http://www.routledge.com/books/details/9780415255592/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spirit of capitalism</a>” (10).</p>
<p>So when did they become old-fashioned? Definitive conclusions await further inquiry. Yet assertions of Anabaptist backwardness can be found as early as the mid-nineteenth century. Take one example from within the community itself: a short 1847 article entitled “The Amish,” by liberal Mennonite elder <a href="http://gameo.org/index.php?title=Harder,_Karl_%281820-1898%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Carl Harder</a> (1820-1898) in provincial Prussia. Harder described the small Amish Mennonite community in the south German states, located several hundred miles away, in explicitly temporal language. In the minister’s telling, his more orthodox coreligionists had willingly distanced themselves from modernity. “Contemporary ways of life are distasteful to them,” he noted. These Amish refused to wear buttons, preferring hooks and eyes. For worship, they met in simple buildings, knelt to pray, and read only a small number of spiritual texts. Not just their churches, but also their homes and everything with which they surrounded themselves appeared, in Harder’s estimation, “quite antiquated.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_773" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-773" style="width: 620px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="773" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/29/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/harders-article/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/harders-article.jpg?fit=1212%2C1293&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1212,1293" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;3.7&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;COOLPIX S6000&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;-62169984000&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;5&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;160&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.016666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Harders Article" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Carl Harder’s brief remarks on “The Amish.” (Monatsschrift für die evangelischen Mennoniten, October 1847, p. 16.)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Carl Harder’s brief remarks on “The Amish.” (Monatsschrift für die evangelischen Mennoniten, October 1847, p. 16.)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/harders-article.jpg?fit=281%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/harders-article.jpg?fit=580%2C619&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-773 size-large jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Carl Harder’s brief remarks on “The Amish.” (Monatsschrift für die evangelischen Mennoniten, October 1847, p. 16.)" width="580" height="618" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/harders-article.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="773" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/29/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/harders-article/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/harders-article.jpg?fit=1212%2C1293&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1212,1293" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;3.7&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;COOLPIX S6000&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;-62169984000&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;5&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;160&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.016666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Harders Article" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Carl Harder’s brief remarks on “The Amish.” (Monatsschrift für die evangelischen Mennoniten, October 1847, p. 16.)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Carl Harder’s brief remarks on “The Amish.” (Monatsschrift für die evangelischen Mennoniten, October 1847, p. 16.)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/harders-article.jpg?fit=281%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/harders-article.jpg?fit=580%2C619&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-773 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524549_962_harders-article.jpg" alt="Carl Harder’s brief remarks on “The Amish.” (Monatsschrift für die evangelischen Mennoniten, October 1847, p. 16.)" width="580" height="618" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-773" class="wp-caption-text">Carl Harder’s brief remarks on “The Amish.” (Monatsschrift für die evangelischen Mennoniten, October 1847, p. 16.)</figcaption></figure>
<p>In the years before the publication of Karl Marx’s major works, such opinions were almost assuredly—at least within the Anabaptist fold—atypical. The first Mennonite in the Prussian east to receive university training and return as a minister, Carl Harder was an unusual figure. After completing his studies at Danzig and Halle in 1845, he went on to become one of the most prolific Mennonite writers and publishers of the nineteenth century. For years, he tutored Prince Hermann of Wied, and he became a lifelong correspondent with the renowned poet and Queen of Romania, Carmen Sylva. In addition to weekly sermons, he delivered public lectures on “Contemporary Politics” and “Modern German Literature,” all the while advocating a new global brand of Freethinking Christian ecumenicalism. If these positions garnered Harder favor among certain Protestant intellectuals, they enraged many of his Neopietist coreligionists. In the 1850s, one assembly of Prussian Mennonite clergy temporarily <a href="http://undpress.nd.edu/books/P01406" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stripped him of his ordination</a> (175-181).</p>
<figure id="attachment_774" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-774" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://gameo.org/index.php?title=File:Harderkarlportsm.jpg&amp;filetimestamp=20130823171536" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img data-attachment-id="774" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/29/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/carl-harder/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/carl-harder.jpg?fit=600%2C600&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="600,600" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Carl Harder" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Carl Harder, 1820-1898 (Ernst Crous, Karl und Ernst Harder, Elbing: Reinhold Kühn, 1927, p. 4.)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Carl Harder, 1820-1898 (Ernst Crous, Karl und Ernst Harder, Elbing: Reinhold Kühn, 1927, p. 4.)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/carl-harder.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/carl-harder.jpg?fit=580%2C580&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-774 size-medium jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Carl Harder, 1820-1898 (Ernst Crous, Karl und Ernst Harder, Elbing: Reinhold Kühn, 1927, p. 4.)" width="300" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/carl-harder.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="774" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/29/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/carl-harder/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/carl-harder.jpg?fit=600%2C600&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="600,600" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Carl Harder" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Carl Harder, 1820-1898 (Ernst Crous, Karl und Ernst Harder, Elbing: Reinhold Kühn, 1927, p. 4.)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Carl Harder, 1820-1898 (Ernst Crous, Karl und Ernst Harder, Elbing: Reinhold Kühn, 1927, p. 4.)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/carl-harder.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/carl-harder.jpg?fit=580%2C580&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-774 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524550_588_carl-harder.jpg" alt="Carl Harder, 1820-1898 (Ernst Crous, Karl und Ernst Harder, Elbing: Reinhold Kühn, 1927, p. 4.)" width="300" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-774" class="wp-caption-text">Carl Harder, 1820-1898 (Ernst Crous, Karl und Ernst Harder, Elbing: Reinhold Kühn, 1927, p. 4.)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Given his long, often bitter personal struggle to liberalize Anabaptism, it is perhaps not surprising that Harder wrote critically of the Amish. The specific language of backwardness, however, was surely not his invention. Beginning in Protestant lecture halls and continuing through discussions with his <a href="http://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/history/twentieth-century-european-history/secularism-and-religion-nineteenth-century-germany-rise-fourth-confession" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Lichtfreunde</em></a> associates, Harder had steeped himself in the discourse and logic of progress. As a fellow native of Konigsberg, he nurtured a special affinity for Immanuel Kant. The Baltic philosopher’s theory of “<a href="http://www.cambridge.org/fr/academic/subjects/politics-international-relations/texts-political-thought/kant-political-writings-2nd-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">perpetual peace</a>,” in particular, seemed to offer Harder a means of retaining a specifically Anabaptist interest in peacemaking while simultaneously supporting Prussian military objectives. And despite his commitment to Christian internationalism, the minister’s early enthusiasm for German unification reflected an appreciation for the philosophy of <a href="http://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/philosophy/philosophy-texts/herder-philosophical-writings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Johann Gottfried Herder</a>. Perhaps most influential were the works of <a href="http://www.cambridge.org/fr/academic/subjects/politics-international-relations/texts-political-thought/hegel-political-writings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G.W.F. Hegel</a>. Just as Harder encouraged the heirs of the Frankfurt Parliament to heed “the will of the <em>Weltgeist</em>,” so did he envision a Mennonitism stripped of its traditionalist trappings (Harder, “Deutschland und Preußen,” <em>Mittheilungen aus dem religiösen Leben</em>, September 1848, 2).</p>
<p>How strong is the link between Anabaptist anti-modernism and teleological views of civilization? Anabaptist thought—perhaps because of its reputation as a peasant theology—has been integrated only poorly into the study of intellectual history. Yet as illustrated by the life and writings of Carl Harder, popular depictions of Amish and Mennonites as holdovers from an earlier time may themselves be, at least partially, the legacy of major European thinkers. While much ink has been spilled over the twentieth-century aversion of conservative Anabaptists toward modernity, comparatively little is known about when or why their various positions emerged in the first place. Examining such questions from an eighteenth or nineteenth-century perspective could prove deeply revealing for historians of Anabaptism, as well as for those seeking to understand how <a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/enemies-of-the-enlightenment-9780195158939?cc=fr&amp;lang=en&amp;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">religious radicals and reactionaries</a> helped shape notions of modernity that are still with us today.</p>
<p><em>Ben Goossen studies modern European history at Harvard University. His research focuses on the nationalization and global migrations of German-speaking Mennonites.</em></p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/when-did-amish-become-old-fashioned/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Philology Among the Disciplines (I): The problem of definitions</title>
		<link>/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/</link>
					<comments>/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 22:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[by John Raimo What is philology? The question may be almost perfectly academic, yet more people have begun to ask it. Scholars such as James Turner and... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><em>by John Raimo</em></p>
<p>What is philology? The question may be almost perfectly academic, yet more people have begun to ask it. Scholars such as <a href="http://press.princeton.edu/titles/10209.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">James Turner</a> and <a href="http://ukcatalogue.oup.com/product/9780199665211.do" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rens Bod</a> argue that philology as a loosely-associated body of practices proved the seedbed of the modern humanities. <a href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/668528" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jerome McGann</a> and others advocate for a return to “philology in a new key” for literary studies, and <a href="http://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674052864" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the comparative scope of latter day philologists</a> continue to grow. All this activity marks something new in a very old history dating back to the classical world, to say nothing of classical studies: what was once a pejorative roughly on par (and perhaps rightly so) with pedantry now readily finds a larger hearing—and <a href="http://www.suhrkamp.de/buecher/was_ist_eine_philologische_frage_-_29543.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">not just in an Anglophone context</a>. Yet what philology meant, means, and holds for all the disciplines remains very much in question.</p>
<figure id="attachment_752" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-752" style="width: 199px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://press.princeton.edu/titles/10209.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="752" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/22/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/81fpmjzxe3l/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/81fpmjzxe3l.jpg?fit=1656%2C2500&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1656,2500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="81FPMJZXe3L" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;James Turner’s “Philology” (Princeton University Press, 2014)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;James Turner’s “Philology” (Princeton University Press, 2014)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/81fpmjzxe3l.jpg?fit=199%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/81fpmjzxe3l.jpg?fit=580%2C876&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-752 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524533_105_81fpmjzxe3l.jpg" alt="James Turner's " width="199" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-752" class="wp-caption-text">James Turner’s “Philology” (Princeton University Press, 2014)</figcaption></figure>
<p>For this reason <a href="http://ndias.nd.edu/academic-events/rome-seminar/presenters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a number of senior scholars</a> and graduate students have gathered at the Notre Dame Institute for Advanced Study in Rome for two weeks under the banner “<a href="http://ndias.nd.edu/academic-events/rome-seminar/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Philology Among the Disciplines</a>.” The seminar organizers deliberately choose the widest ambit for discussion: lectures and seminars have revolved around epistemology, philosophy, exegesis, hermeneutics, traditions, practices, and above all disciplinary histories. In the first week, those entailed archaeology, art history, classics, history, and philosophy. Perhaps it’s to the credit of the discussion that any clear answers may be receding, however. What follows consists then more of my own thoughts and observations as we head into the second week (and a follow-up post later on).</p>
<p>If one thing is clear, it would be that philology can be extended past the textual practices of emendation, collation, and historical semantics often associated with the term. The breaking point is less clear. As per the archaeologist <a href="http://ndias.nd.edu/academic-events/rome-seminar/presenters/alain-schnapp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alain Schnapp</a>, philology becomes almost an ahistorical means of historical reflection. Material remains of one sort or another evoke memories in two directions: a present long past which planned for the future via monuments, coins, and so forth, and the possibility (or at least rhetoric) of a direct connection to the past from our current present. The problem of reconstruction versus memory rears its head, however, to say nothing of dropping what we might call philological rigor in imagining that we can skip over the intervening historical distance. The sheer materiality of stone or of syntax affords this illusion of direct access.</p>
<p>Put another way, there’s no such thing as an isolated ruin, vestige, or trace of the past. Here one might well consider numismatics or the study of currency like ancient coins. Yet this hardly remains a signature delusion of archaeologists. The same goes for texts no matter how thoroughly or obsessively contextualized and reconstructed, the self-aware knowledge of accumulated scholarship (often centuries’ worth) in the best cases non-withstanding.</p>
<p>According to <a href="http://www.germanistik.uni-halle.de/mitarbeiterinnen/prof._decultot/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Elisabeth Décultot</a>, the case of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johann_Joachim_Winckelmann" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Johann Joachim Winckelmann</a> sheds some light on this dynamic. How could philology buttress interpretations of art? Or might it serve to construct universal histories, especially those adjudicating between civilizations and ages? In the case of Winckelmann as well as of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anne_Claude_de_Caylus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Comte de Caylus</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johann_Gottfried_Herder" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Herder</a>, historians of scholarship can find philology in its capacity as a <em>Hilfswissenschaft</em> or subsidiary discipline of sorts. This might entail claims of societal progress and artistic achievement held on par with a respective language—especially when broaching rather mistier sorts of Ur-origins. Hence for Winckelmann, philology ran parallel to and partly tempered aesthetic experience.</p>
<p>But philology could also simply mean employing philological prowess as a sort of polemical sidearm. Errors of reading could disqualify an opponent; those with little Latin and less Greek still know about this. Philology otherwise evidently proved crucial as means of professional distinction. Winckelmann was not simply a connoisseur practicing on an exponentially broader canvas but rather positioning himself as something like a modern art historian.</p>
<figure id="attachment_751" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-751" style="width: 620px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Ara_Pacis_Rom.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img data-attachment-id="751" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/22/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/776px-ara_pacis_rom/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/776px-ara_pacis_rom.jpg?fit=776%2C600&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="776,600" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="776px-Ara_Pacis_Rom" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Ara Pacis in Rome&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;The Ara Pacis in Rome&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/776px-ara_pacis_rom.jpg?fit=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/776px-ara_pacis_rom.jpg?fit=580%2C448&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-751 size-large jetpack-lazy-image" alt="The Ara Pacis in Rome" width="580" height="448" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/776px-ara_pacis_rom.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="751" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/22/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/776px-ara_pacis_rom/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/776px-ara_pacis_rom.jpg?fit=776%2C600&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="776,600" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="776px-Ara_Pacis_Rom" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Ara Pacis in Rome&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;The Ara Pacis in Rome&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/776px-ara_pacis_rom.jpg?fit=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/776px-ara_pacis_rom.jpg?fit=580%2C448&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-751 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524534_811_776px-ara_pacis_rom.jpg" alt="The Ara Pacis in Rome" width="580" height="448" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-751" class="wp-caption-text">The Ara Pacis in Rome</figcaption></figure>
<p>A trip to <a href="http://en.arapacis.it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the Ara Pacis</a> in Rome bodied out some underlying issues here. Perhaps especially in looking to classical remains, philology can find itself in the double-traffic between image and text. That is, it serves as a check (rather like the ‘semantic check’ theorized in <em>Begriffsgeschichte</em>) on the range of possible interpretations afforded by historical objects, texts or otherwise. Here philology can run counter to the sort of contextualization amounting to the process of association—often carried to the extent of an object taken to represent the whole of a civilization—and embedding historical traces into external narratives of a certain sort.</p>
<p>Put another way, according to <a href="http://classics.nd.edu/faculty/classics-faculty/martin-bloomer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Martin Bloomer</a>, philology presupposes limits as it carries its own. It almost unconsciously entertains hermeneutic presuppositions: that a whole exists to be reconstructed from a fragment, that correct emendations and interpretations exist, that historical unities of style can be discovered, that synecdoche might recover a worldview, that the one best reader (e.g. the most talented linguist) gets to write the commentary and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paratext" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">paratext</a>, that monumentality and preservation best serve interpretation. At its best, however, philology can also prove “self-policing” in such a way as to ideally form a toolbox of sorts, namely one comprising practices (emendation, error-detection, &amp;c.) within ‘negative’ or falsifiable and hence professional constraints.</p>
<figure id="attachment_750" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-750" style="width: 481px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herodotus#/media/File:Dedication_page_for_the_Historiae_by_Herodotus_printed_at_Venice_1494.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img data-attachment-id="750" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/22/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494.jpg?fit=927%2C1400&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="927,1400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Dedication_page_for_the_Historiae_by_Herodotus_printed_at_Venice_1494" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Dedication page for the Historiae by the Greek historian Herodotus, translated into Latin by Lorenzo Valla (1494)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Dedication page for the Historiae by the Greek historian Herodotus, translated into Latin by Lorenzo Valla (1494)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494.jpg?fit=199%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494.jpg?fit=580%2C876&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-750 jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Dedication page for the Historiae by the Greek historian Herodotus, translated into Latin by Lorenzo Valla (1494)" width="481" height="726" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="750" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/22/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494.jpg?fit=927%2C1400&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="927,1400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Dedication_page_for_the_Historiae_by_Herodotus_printed_at_Venice_1494" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Dedication page for the Historiae by the Greek historian Herodotus, translated into Latin by Lorenzo Valla (1494)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Dedication page for the Historiae by the Greek historian Herodotus, translated into Latin by Lorenzo Valla (1494)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494.jpg?fit=199%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494.jpg?fit=580%2C876&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-750" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524536_804_dedication_page_for_the_historiae_by_herodotus_printed_at_venice_1494.jpg" alt="Dedication page for the Historiae by the Greek historian Herodotus, translated into Latin by Lorenzo Valla (1494)" width="481" height="726" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-750" class="wp-caption-text">Historiae by the Greek historian Herodotus, translated into Latin by Lorenzo Valla (1494)</figcaption></figure>
<p>For <a href="http://sites01.lsu.edu/wp/history/faculty/suzanne-marchand/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Suzanne Marchand</a>, the later receptions of Herodotus among historians demonstrated how hard this proves in practice. His unusually complicated text poses more problems (and possibilities) than I can address here. In brief though, what a broader history of the champions and detractors of the same “father of history” and the fantastical “father of lies” demonstrates is that regimes of philological truth exist: that is, Herodotus has been variously held to be accurate or false in different ways at different times, and all of them broadly convincing for period readers.</p>
<p>Where does that leave us? For philosopher <a href="https://www.unilu.ch/en/faculties/faculty-of-humanities-and-social-sciences/institutes-departements-and-research-centres/department-of-philosophy/staff/christiane-schildknecht/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Christiane Schildknecht</a> and classicist <a href="https://socialthought.uchicago.edu/directory/glenn-w-most" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Glenn W. Most</a>, philology amounts to a renewed focus upon epistemology. For the former, this renews the distinction of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Descriptive_knowledge" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">propositional from non-propositional knowledge</a> in the act of interpretation. Hermeneutics, aesthetics, and historical scholarship hold equal weight and distinguish different values of truth. For the latter, philology implies a return to the history of science. A ‘top-down’ account of material practices of philology might stand in for the best history. Here one might look to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/?title=Carl_Friedrich_Gauss" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Carl Friedrich Gauss</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Lachmann" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Karl Lachmann</a> alike: how they came to distinguish between random and systematic errors is one story, but how both came to see that even random errors could be consistent proves another. Such implicit epistemological challenges have never left scientists or scholars in the humanities.</p>
<figure id="attachment_749" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-749" style="width: 620px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img data-attachment-id="749" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/22/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/img_4112/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/img_4112.jpg?fit=1280%2C960&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1280,960" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;2.2&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 6&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1434313140&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.15&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;32&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.0030120481927711&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_4112" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/img_4112.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/img_4112.jpg?fit=580%2C435&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-749 size-large jetpack-lazy-image" alt="IMG_4112" width="580" height="435" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/img_4112.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="749" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/06/22/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/img_4112/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/img_4112.jpg?fit=1280%2C960&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1280,960" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;2.2&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 6&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1434313140&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.15&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;32&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.0030120481927711&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_4112" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/img_4112.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/img_4112.jpg?fit=580%2C435&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-749 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524537_223_img_4112.jpg" alt="IMG_4112" width="580" height="435" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-749" class="wp-caption-text">The Coliseum at Rome (courtesy of the author)</figcaption></figure>
<p>In both Schildknecht and Most’s telling then, philology becomes more a matter of methodological orientation or even self-consciousness. Beyond a body of certain textual practices, philology serves as a willingness to revise theory in light of pragmatic and experimental difficulties rather than vice-versa. Here philology’s polemical value today also comes to light in the age of ‘<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/06/26/books/review/the-mechanic-muse-what-is-distant-reading.html?_r=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">distant reading</a>,’ the long ascendancy of theoretical schools in various humanistic disciplines, and pedagogical trends and desires. To return to philology’s position today, however, this requires more historical scrutiny than ever. Back-formations of what philology never in truth was easily enough serve for a counter-politics of sorts. Nothing would be further from the historical truth of philology across and between the ages.</p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/philology-among-the-disciplines-i-the-problem-of-definitions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From and for the Republic of Letters</title>
		<link>/from-and-for-the-republic-of-letters/</link>
					<comments>/from-and-for-the-republic-of-letters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 23:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/from-and-for-the-republic-of-letters/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Herman Moll’s A new map of the whole world with the trade winds (1736) The JHI Blog welcomes pitches for guest posts from across the world and... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<figure id="attachment_887" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-887" style="width: 620px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Moll_-_A_new_map_of_the_whole_world_with_the_trade_winds.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="887" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/08/27/from-and-for-the-republic-of-letters/800px-moll_-_a_new_map_of_the_whole_world_with_the_trade_winds/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/800px-moll_-_a_new_map_of_the_whole_world_with_the_trade_winds.png?fit=800%2C619&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="800,619" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="800px-Moll_-_A_new_map_of_the_whole_world_with_the_trade_winds" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Herman Moll’s A new map of the whole world with the trade winds (1736)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Herman Moll’s A new map of the whole world with the trade winds (1736)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/800px-moll_-_a_new_map_of_the_whole_world_with_the_trade_winds.png?fit=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/800px-moll_-_a_new_map_of_the_whole_world_with_the_trade_winds.png?fit=580%2C449&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-887 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524626_665_800px-moll_-_a_new_map_of_the_whole_world_with_the_trade_winds.png" alt="Herman Moll's A new map of the whole world with the trade winds (1736)" width="580" height="449" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-887" class="wp-caption-text">Herman Moll’s A new map of the whole world with the trade winds (1736)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The JHI Blog welcomes pitches for guest posts from across the world and across the republic of letters. Our readers will also know that we’ve happily branched out into reviews of conferences, public lectures, and exhibitions. We would like to extend an invitation to new contributors interested in writing the latter sort of posts as well for both public and (if appropriate) closed events of broader interest to intellectual historians. And here the new academic year has already begun to furnish several interesting events beginning with a <a href="http://isih.history.ox.ac.uk/?p=4644" target="_blank" rel="noopener">conference on interdisciplinarity and pluralism at the University of St. Andrews</a> and <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/specialization-run-amok-contextualizing-denis-diderot-tickets-18286569622?aff=es2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">open</a> <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/thomas-hobbes-and-the-iconography-of-the-state-tickets-18286622781" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lectures</a> at the <a href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/history/events/london-summer-school" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Summer School in Intellectual History</a>. See our calendar feature above or in the sidebar for more happenings in the world of intellectual history, and please don’t hesitate to contact us here with news of others we might have missed or with an offer to review one that looks promising.</p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --></p>
<div class="relpost-thumb-wrapper"><!-- filter-class --></p>
<div class="relpost-thumb-container">
<h3>Related posts:</h3>
<p><!-- related_posts_thumbnails --></p>
<ul id="related_posts_thumbnails" style="list-style-type:none; list-style-position: inside; padding: 0; margin:0">
<li><img class="relpost-post-image jetpack-lazy-image" alt="3371" width="150" height="150" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/3371-150x150.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" class="relpost-post-image" alt="3371" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524626_933_3371-150x150.jpg" width="150" height="150" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><span class="rpth_list_content">Dispatches from Princeton’s History of Science Colloquium: Jutta Schickore’s “Contributions to a His&#8230;</span></li>
<li><img class="relpost-post-image jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Days of Letters in the Republic" width="150" height="150" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524626_177_Owl-for-bloog-2-4.png" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" class="relpost-post-image" alt="Days of Letters in the Republic" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524626_483_Owl-for-bloog-2-4.png" width="150" height="150" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><span class="rpth_list_content">Days of Letters in the Republic</span></li>
<li><img class="relpost-post-image jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Dispatches from the Republic of Letters" width="150" height="150" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524626_177_Owl-for-bloog-2-4.png" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" class="relpost-post-image" alt="Dispatches from the Republic of Letters" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524626_483_Owl-for-bloog-2-4.png" width="150" height="150" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><span class="rpth_list_content">Dispatches from the Republic of Letters</span></li>
</ul>
<p><!-- close related_posts_thumbnails --></div>
<p><!-- close filter class --></div>
<p><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/from-and-for-the-republic-of-letters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Jules Verne would roll over in his grave,&#8221; or Döblin on the Future</title>
		<link>/jules-verne-would-roll-over-in-his-grave-or-doblin-on-the-future/</link>
					<comments>/jules-verne-would-roll-over-in-his-grave-or-doblin-on-the-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 05:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/jules-verne-would-roll-over-in-his-grave-or-doblin-on-the-future/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[by guest contributor Carolyn Taratko Migrants streaming into Europe’s cities, postcolonial conflicts brought home, Greenland’s melting ice sheet, scientists emancipated from nature’s constraints through the use of... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><em>by guest contributor Carolyn Taratko</em></p>
<p>Migrants streaming into Europe’s cities, postcolonial conflicts brought home, Greenland’s melting ice sheet, scientists emancipated from nature’s constraints through the use of genetic engineering; these sound like today’s headlines, but in fact they come from the pages of Alfred Döblin’s novel <a href="http://www.fischerverlage.de/buch/werke_band_1_berge_meere_und_giganten/9783100155511"><em>Berge Meere und Giganten</em></a> (1924). It narrates the story of humans between the twenty-third and twenty-eighth centuries. Along general lines, it is a story of bipolar world of great, urbanized powers, East and West, a catastrophic war (the <em>Uralische Krieg</em>), and the quest for new areas of settlement in Greenland to relieve growing population pressure. Its epic form allows for many digressions: descriptions of landscapes modified by technology, war and hubris, accounts of battles and love triangles burdened by cultural baggage in a world of empowered, even ferocious women. It is, in one word, staggering. The force of the imagination behind this work is a wonder in itself.</p>
<figure id="attachment_373" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-373" style="width: 211px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfred_D%C3%B6blin#mediaviewer/File:Alfred_Doeblin_1930a.jpg"><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="373" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/03/11/jules-verne-would-roll-over-in-his-grave-or-doblin-on-the-future/alfred_doeblin_1930a/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/alfred_doeblin_1930a.jpg?fit=444%2C631&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="444,631" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Alfred_Doeblin_1930a" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Alfred Döblin (c. 1930s)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/alfred_doeblin_1930a.jpg?fit=211%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/alfred_doeblin_1930a.jpg?fit=444%2C631&amp;ssl=1" class="size-medium wp-image-373" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524266_728_alfred_doeblin_1930a.jpg" alt="Alfred Döblin (c. 1930s)" width="211" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-373" class="wp-caption-text">Alfred Döblin (c. 1930s)</figcaption></figure>
<p>This earlier novel by the author of the famed <em>Berlin, Alexanderplatz </em>runs over 600 pages and resists any neat summary. <a href="http://www.zeit.de/1978/25/im-wettlauf-mit-den-utopien">Günter Grass</a> once described it as “written as if under visionary influence.” Döblin clarified his goal: to write so that “Jules Verne would roll over in his grave” (Döblin, AW, Brief an Efraim Frisch, 2. Nov. 1920, 120). Yet it has largely been forgotten, partly due to the fact that scholars are unsure of how to handle such works. Among historians utopian/dystopian works are a relatively underexplored source, liable to be written off as curiosities. It is as if the act of marveling at their visionary power, at the uncanny “accuracy” of the predictions held within such fictions somehow precludes taking them seriously.</p>
<p>Döblin began work on <em>Berge Meere und Giganten</em> in the fall of 1921, a year after the publication of his historical novel <em><a href="http://www.fischerverlage.de/buch/wallenstein/9783104029153">Wallenstein</a></em>, set during the Thirty Years War. He oriented the project around the question, “What will become of man, should he continue to live in this way?” The time he spent researching, he reported to friends, was marked by extreme physical exertion and a neurotic state that bordered on mania. Döblin’s time at a military hospital Alsace-Lorraine during the First World War had brought him into direct contact with the horrors of the war that serve as the origin of this fictional universe. The recurring images of flesh mangled by machines that appear in the novel are hardly writerly abstractions.</p>
<p>Wider political forces also gave life to this novel. Contemporary observers and generations of historians have commented on the crisis-ridden years of the Weimar Republic. There is no doubt that, in Detlev Peukert’s words, the “birth trauma” of the Weimar Republic in the November Revolution and the Treaty of Versailles left the German government vulnerable to a prolonged crisis of legitimacy. Saddled with reparations, bound with demands for disarmament and dealing with maimed territory, the young republic faced challenges both at home and abroad. But for Döblin it was the failure of the 1918/19 Revolution (which he would later make the subject of a four-volume historical novel) that proved to be the most colossal disappointment. How to move forward? What had once seemed to be the best hope for the future – Social Democracy– had been largely discredited and hollowed out. Döblin experienced outrage, supplanted by recognition.</p>
<p>His outrage was best articulated in his journalism from these years. But even for as sharp an eye as Döblin, reportage and satire had its limits. Within the framework of a historical novel, Döblin was able to <a href="http://www.fischerverlage.de/buch/der_historische_roman_und_wir/9783104022857" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pursue a different “truth.”</a> The novel, he wrote, is privilege to its own truth—not the “facts” of journalists or of white-bearded historians (Döblin seems quite unimpressed with the latter group), but personal and social truth (<em>Echtsheitscharakter</em>). It could address gender relations, love, marriage, friendship—in short, things that no newspaper and serious history book could illuminate. Such were the arguments Döblin marshaled in favor of the historical novel, whose setting in the past granted it a certain degree of plausibility. A novel set in the distant future failed to offer such security.</p>
<p>If Döblin was convinced of the power of the historical novel to represent and critique, why did he spend years drafting a novel set in a distant future, a space that would unsettle the reader and court the bounds of plausibility? We can see from his years of embittered reportage that Döblin was ready to take his critique not only of Weimar Germany and of the increasingly apparent tendencies of urbanization, mass culture, rationalization in the “the West” one step further.</p>
<p>Döblin did not make the jump to utopian fiction in 1921 in isolation. Utopian works gained wider currency as a genre and intellectual project in the early twentieth century. Novelists turned towards future-oriented, experimental forms, academics began to take utopia seriously as objects of analysis, and across the political spectrum in Germany such projects were embraced as a means of representing a world worth striving for. As the <a href="https://archive.org/stream/deutscherundscha183stutuoft#page/320/mode/2up" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sociologist Hans Freyer wrote in 1920</a>, utopia constituted a “creative form of practical rationality.” <a href="http://www.degruyter.com/view/product/225707" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rüdiger Graf</a> has identified the transformation that the term “utopia” underwent in the early twentieth century, shedding its earlier fantastical and pejorative sense to become recognized as a form of critical debate at the very heart of the emerging social-scientific project. The intensified interest in utopia followed from a general acceptance that these constructions (no longer just fictions) acted as a determining force in political behavior. Graf has charted the development of utopian studies alongside sociology; the two represented twin approaches to understanding the crisis of the 1920s. In the wake of the World War, the Russian Revolution and revolutionary events that swept across Europe, a dawning awareness of the contingency and malleability of circumstances was accompanied by an acceptance of utopian discourse. Graf refers to this process as a radicalization of Reinhart Koselleck’s concept of the Sattelzeit: an intensified encounter in which the <a href="http://www.suhrkamp.de/buecher/zeitschichten-reinhart_koselleck_29256.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">horizon of expectation overtakes that of experience</a>.</p>
<p>And here we must return to Döblin. Seen in this light, <em>Berge Meere und Giganten </em>is no mere flight of fancy; it is a rigorous exercise in historical imagination and continuity. Within Döblin’s novel we can see the horizon of expectation playing out in front of our eyes in lurid detail, defying any neat summary.</p>
<p><em><a href="http://as.vanderbilt.edu/history/bio/carolyn-taratko" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Carolyn Taratko</a> is a PhD candidate at Vanderbilt University. For the 2014-2015 academic year, she is based at the Freie Universität in Berlin. Her current research focuses on resource management and perceptions of crisis in late nineteenth- and early twentieth century Germany.</em></p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/jules-verne-would-roll-over-in-his-grave-or-doblin-on-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Meredith Ray, Daughters of Alchemy</title>
		<link>/book-review-meredith-ray-daughters-of-alchemy/</link>
					<comments>/book-review-meredith-ray-daughters-of-alchemy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 14:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/book-review-meredith-ray-daughters-of-alchemy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[by guest contributor Elisabeth Brander Alchemy, and its association with the quest for the always-elusive philosopher’s stone, is one of the most fascinating aspects of early modern... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><i>by guest contributor Elisabeth Brander</i></p>
<p>Alchemy, and its association with the quest for the always-elusive philosopher’s stone, is one of the most fascinating aspects of early modern science. It was not only a tool to effect the transmutation of metals and create medical remedies, but also a philosophical and theological pursuit. Its most famous practitioners include John Dee, Isaac Newton, and Theophrastus Bombastus von Hohenheim, more commonly known as Paracelsus. The alchemical work of Paracelsus in particular has attracted considerable academic interest: from Walter Pagel’s <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=wO244WXEBKcC&amp;lpg=PP4&amp;ots=pynoxT5QEu&amp;dq=walter%20pagel%20paracelsus&amp;pg=PP4#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false">analysis</a> of his medical philosophy, published in the mid-twentieth century, to Charles Webster’s <a href="http://yalepress.yale.edu/book.asp?isbn=9780300139112">more recent studies</a> of Paracelsus’ social and theological mission.</p>
<p><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="688" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/05/20/book-review-meredith-ray-daughters-of-alchemy/doa/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/doa.jpg?fit=447%2C680&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="447,680" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="doa" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/doa.jpg?fit=197%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/doa.jpg?fit=447%2C680&amp;ssl=1" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-688" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524470_428_doa.jpg" alt="doa" width="197" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript>These men might be well-known, but they were not the only alchemical practitioners. Tara Nummedal has <a href="www.press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/A/bo5506197.html">shed light on</a> the career of Anna Maria Zieglerin, a sixteenth-century German alchemist in the court of Duke Julius of Braunschweig-Wolfenbüttel, whose work focused on childbearing and fertility. This is complemented by the work of Alisha Rankin, who has <a href="www.press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/P/bo14397331.html">brought attention to</a> what she terms “noble empirics”: German noblewomen who created medical remedies using their empirically gained knowledge. Meredith Ray’s new study <a href="www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674504233"><i>Daughters of Alchemy</i></a> continues this discussion of female practitioners. Her analysis of Caterina Sforza, the noblewoman from whom the Medici grand dukes were descended, provides an Italian counterpart to Rankin’s empirics. Sforza was actively engaged in the scientific empiricism of the age, and was a collector of “experiments”: personal recipes based on alchemical principles that could fulfill a variety of useful functions. Some were used to make cosmetics or medicinal remedies, and others were used for the traditional alchemical pursuits of creating—or mimicking—gold. These recipes reveal the ways in which alchemy was a practical pursuit for noblewomen, whether as a means to preserve health and beauty, or maintain control of their finances.</p>
<p>Sforza wrote her recipes in a private manuscript—a true “book of secrets”—but in the sixteenth century these compilations of recipes were also published, forming a popular literary genre. While these books contained knowledge that appealed to both sexes, many of their recipes offered advice tailored specifically to females, such as how to make breasts small and firm. This indicates that women were an intended audience for these texts. Yet only one book of secrets, the <i>Secrets of Signora Isabella Cortese</i>, is attributed to a female author, and even the Secrets’ female authorship is dubious. Ray ties this male authorship of books of secrets to the wider early modern desire to uncover the so-called “secrets of women.” This special knowledge of the female body, which was believed to be possessed only by women, was a topic of great interest for early modern medical practitioners; and Ray argues this is echoed in the male authorship of books of secrets. But even though these works were most often written by men, their distinctly feminine content is an indication of women’s continuing interest in practical alchemy.</p>
<p>Although her monograph is titled <i>Daughters of Alchemy</i>, Ray’s focus extends beyond alchemical practice. The second half of the work shifts away from alchemy and towards natural philosophy, particularly how women deployed it in literature. The Venetian authors Moderata Fonte and Lucrezia Marinella used their understanding of scientific discourse and natural philosophy as weapons in the <i>querelle des femmes</i>, the ongoing literary debate about the proper role and status of women. Both Fonte and Marinella incorporated scientific learning into their narrative works to make keen observations regarding the inherent intelligence of women and their equality with men. While these two authors did not engage with the empirical practice of Sforza and Cortese, their literary output shows that women could engage with scientific knowledge outside the confines of a university. In that sense they are similar to the seventeenth-century English noblewoman Margaret Cavendish, another early feminist author and natural philosopher whose scientific contributions have attracted academic attention in recent years.</p>
<p>Ray’s final two case studies are the most directly engaged with the so-called Scientific Revolution. Camilla Erculiani, an apothecary from Padua, published her Letters, a scientific treatise in epistolary format, in 1584. This work combined her knowledge of Galenic and Aristotelian thought with her understanding of alchemical processes to describe the causes of the great flood. Margherita Sarrochi, who was famous for her learning and hosted a salon that attracted many leading scientific figures, did not publish any scientific works of her own. This did not, however, prevent her from participating in scientific culture. She corresponded with no less a figure than Galileo: not only about her own epic poem <i>Scanderbeide</i>, but also about his astronomic discoveries. The letters of others corroborate that a high value was placed on her opinions, and emphasize the prominent role she played within her scientific network.</p>
<p>None of the women Ray describes held formal positions at the great European universities, and the vast majority of published scientific treatises were written by men. But as the work of Ray and others are making increasingly apparent, early modern scientific culture was not limited to male academic circles. Women practiced alchemy within their households, incorporated scientific learning into their literary pursuits, and offered their opinions on scientific treatises. As Ray states in her introduction, “It is not women who are missing from the picture: it is our lens that must be adjusted to perceive them” (4). <i>Daughters of Alchemy</i> certainly does this.</p>
<p><i>Elisabeth Brander is the rare book librarian at the Bernard Becker Medical Library of Washington University in St. Louis. Her academic interests include anatomical illustration in the early modern period, the history of obstetrics, and the connections between magic and medicine.</i></p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-meredith-ray-daughters-of-alchemy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medardo Rosso’s Casts, Copies and Prints: Illuminating the Artist’s Process</title>
		<link>/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/</link>
					<comments>/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 11:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By guest contributor Jeremy Bleeke Rosso in his studio in Milan, 1883. From Margaret Scolari Barr, Medardo Rosso, Museum of Modern Art, (1963), 18. The life and... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><em>By guest contributor Jeremy Bleeke</em></p>
<figure id="attachment_521" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-521" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="521" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/fullsizerender/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/fullsizerender.jpg?fit=3264%2C2448&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3264,2448" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;2.2&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 5s&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1427811768&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.15&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;320&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.041666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;latitude&quot;:&quot;40.736675&quot;,&quot;longitude&quot;:&quot;-73.992972222222&quot;}" data-image-title="FullSizeRender" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Rosso in his studio in Milan, 1883. From Margaret Scolari Barr, Medardo Rosso, Museum of Modern Art, (1963), 18.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/fullsizerender.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/fullsizerender.jpg?fit=580%2C435&amp;ssl=1" class="size-medium wp-image-521" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524357_274_fullsizerender.jpg" alt="Rosso in his studio in Milan, 1883. From Margaret Scolari Barr, Medardo Rosso, Museum of Modern Art, (1963), 18." width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-521" class="wp-caption-text">Rosso in his studio in Milan, 1883. From Margaret Scolari Barr, Medardo Rosso, Museum of Modern Art, (1963), 18.</figcaption></figure>
<p>The life and work of <a href="http://www.moma.org/collection/artist.php?artist_id=5036">Medardo Rosso</a> (1858-1928) has traditionally been divided by scholars into two phases: an initial period of creative fecundity, and a late period characterized by processes of reproduction, repetition, and copying, generally seen as a failure of imagination and vitality. From the final two decades of the nineteenth century until 1906, the sculptor created around 50 subjects in various media (characters such as the <em>Procuress</em>, the <em>Sacristan</em>, the <em>Laughing Woman</em>, and the <em>Jewish Boy</em>); Rosso then ceased to make “new” sculpture, and until his death he was mostly involved in recasting and promoting existing work. Recently, however, art historians have begun to challenge this schema, demonstrating ways in which serial production spanned Rosso’s oeuvre and challenging the dichotomy between phases of authentic originals and derivative copies.</p>
<p>In 2003, an exhibition titled <a href="http://yalepress.yale.edu/book.asp?isbn=9780300100334"><em>Medardo Rosso: Second Impressions</em></a> focused exclusively on Rosso’s work after the so-called end of his creative period in 1906. The show assembled series cast in different materials and uncovered the methods by which Rosso produced them. The curators found, for example, that Rosso cast with wax in the same way that he cast in bronze: working from a plaster mold that had been created from a clay model. Rosso’s fascination with “<a href="http://www.pubhist.com/article/26480/medardo-rosso">the range of possibilities inherent in the nature of the casting process</a>” became clear.</p>
<p>Several years later, <a href="http://www.researchgate.net/profile/Francesca_Bacci2/publications">Francesca Bacci</a> published a portion of her exhaustive study of Rosso’s photography (the subject of her doctoral dissertation), illuminating a facet of his production that had been largely ignored or misunderstood (Bacci, “<a href="http://liverpool.metapress.com/content/jh85258g418317r8/">Sculpting the immaterial, modelling the light: presenting Medardo Rosso’s photographic <em>oeuvre</em></a>”). Bacci argues that in the two decades before his death, Rosso was in fact highly productive, using photography to explore certain cherished methodologies and techniques that he had developed in his sculptural practice. For example, Rosso was famous for insisting that his sculptures must be viewed from one angle, as if they were paintings. As Bacci notes: “This viewing modality is the visual equivalent of observing a flat object. Because a photograph is an exact two-dimensional representation of an image perceived from a unique point of view, the best visual translation of Rosso’s aesthetic theory lies in the photographs of his own sculpture” (Bacci, 223). Bacci argues that the photographs are not means to an end (studio aids or documentary evidence) but stand-alone works of art.</p>
<p>As this new wave of scholarship suggests, Rosso (like his contemporary Rodin) was fundamentally concerned with a discourse that would become one of the main strands of twentieth-century art history and theory: the relationship between an original and its copies. So far in advance of the later conceptual games of Andy Warhol, Cindy Sherman, or Sherrie Levine, Rosso’s play with casts, copies and photographs has a freshness and innocence (born partially out of the relative youth of photography in his day) that is at once surprising and challenging. Far from seeing serial production as a repetitive exercise of duplication, Rosso opened a dialogue in his final decades between the sculptural and the photographic, using each medium to enrich one’s experience of the other.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="523" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1.jpg?fit=6048%2C4320&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4320" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 22, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413936000&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141022_NY_CIMA_Rosso_634_CP (1)" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 22, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1.jpg?fit=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1.jpg?fit=580%2C414&amp;ssl=1" class="alignleft wp-image-523 size-medium jetpack-lazy-image" alt="20141022_NY_CIMA_Rosso_634_CP (1)" width="300" height="214" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="523" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1.jpg?fit=6048%2C4320&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4320" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 22, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413936000&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141022_NY_CIMA_Rosso_634_CP (1)" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 22, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1.jpg?fit=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1.jpg?fit=580%2C414&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignleft wp-image-523 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524360_477_20141022_ny_cima_rosso_634_cp-1.jpg" alt="20141022_NY_CIMA_Rosso_634_CP (1)" width="300" height="214" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></p>
<p>Now, at the <a href="http://www.italianmodernart.org/">Center for Italian Modern Art</a> in New York, an elegant exhibition of Rosso’s work explores the long-overlooked photographic dimension of the sculptor’s research and its relationship to his sculpture (a sister show, also drawn from the holdings of the <a href="http://www.medardorosso.org/">Rosso museum in Barzio</a>, Italy, is being staged concurrently in <a href="http://www.gam-milano.com/mostre-ed-eventi/mostre-in-corso/">Milan</a>). The CIMA show brings together 11 sculptures, dozens of drawings, and over 50 original photographs taken by the artist. While we wait for CIMA to publish its research on the photographs and sculptures, a visit to the exhibition immerses the visitor in the physical evidence of the sculptor’s highly singular creative process.</p>
<figure id="attachment_524" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-524" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img data-attachment-id="524" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp.jpg?fit=6048%2C4104&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4104" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 22, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413936000&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141022_NY_CIMA_Rosso_526final_CP" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 22, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Rosso’s photographs on display at CIMA.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp.jpg?fit=300%2C204&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp.jpg?fit=580%2C394&amp;ssl=1" class="size-medium wp-image-524 jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Rosso's photographs on display at CIMA." width="300" height="204" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="524" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp.jpg?fit=6048%2C4104&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4104" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 22, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413936000&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141022_NY_CIMA_Rosso_526final_CP" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 22, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Rosso’s photographs on display at CIMA.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp.jpg?fit=300%2C204&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp.jpg?fit=580%2C394&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-524" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524362_296_20141022_ny_cima_rosso_526final_cp.jpg" alt="Rosso's photographs on display at CIMA." width="300" height="204" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-524" class="wp-caption-text">Rosso’s photographs on display at CIMA.</figcaption></figure>
<p>CIMA, which opened in SoHo in 2013, occupies an airy, uncluttered suite of rooms; filled with light and beautifully renovated, it is a rare, uplifting space for viewing art. Stepping off the elevator, visitors are met with Rosso’s photograph <a href="http://image.slidesharecdn.com/01fiiimpressionismo-130429164444-phpapp01/95/impressionismo-25-638.jpg?cb=1376639917"><em>Impression of an Omnibus </em></a>(1884-89) taken of a plaster sculpture, now destroyed, depicting five people arrayed side by side. In a vitrine below this image are series of photographs made from it: individual fragments in which one of the characters is subjected to an array of different treatments. In one series Rosso focuses on the young woman second from the left, photographing and re-photographing existing prints of the sculpture. The result is a subtle process of abstraction, in which the figure is pared down to its essential form. From one image to the next, the woman transitions from solidly present – part of the plaster mass that is visible around her – to suggestively dematerialized. Rosso crops her more closely, and the act of re-photographing washes out the picture, so that the shadows around her face and head are all that distinguish her from the white background. In her focused, straight-forward gaze, we are reminded of the description of Clarissa’s daughter in <em>Mrs. Dalloway</em>, whose ride on the roof of a London omnibus might read as an ekphrasis of this image: “the breeze slightly disarrayed her; the heat gave her cheeks the pallor of white painted wood; and her fine eyes, having no eyes to meet, gazed ahead, blank, bright, with the staring incredible innocence of sculpture.”</p>
<p>Moving into the main exhibition space, we see serial production take familiar form in Rosso’s sculpture, most notably in three iterations of the <em>Madame Noblet</em>, executed between 1897 and 1914 in plaster, bronze, and wax over plaster. Playing with imitations of materiality, Rosso gives the lightweight substances of plaster and wax heft and solidity, as if they are rock from which Madame Noblet has been hewn. Two versions of the <em>Sick Child</em>, in wax and plaster, provide a foil to the roughly handled heads. Here, the amber wax that covers the child’s face seems as delicate as skin itself. The nearby series of photographs open a provocative dialogue with these sculptures. Just as the photographic images were formed through a temporal process of exposure onto a negative, so the sculpture seems to act as a kind of receptacle of the light, becoming sharper or more diffuse depending on the ambient conditions. In the rooms of CIMA, flooded with natural light, Rosso’s play of materials can be appreciated to best effect. As the cold light of morning transitions to the golden light of early evening, these sculptures, which seem to absorb and radiate the light, must transform in fascinating ways.</p>
<figure id="attachment_526" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-526" style="width: 620px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="526" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp.jpg?fit=6048%2C4320&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4320" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413763200&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141020_NY_CIMA_Rosso_099_CP" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;“Sick Child” in wax and plaster.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp.jpg?fit=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp.jpg?fit=580%2C414&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-526 size-large jetpack-lazy-image" alt="&quot;Sick Child&quot; in wax and plaster." width="580" height="414" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="526" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp.jpg?fit=6048%2C4320&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4320" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413763200&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141020_NY_CIMA_Rosso_099_CP" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;“Sick Child” in wax and plaster.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp.jpg?fit=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp.jpg?fit=580%2C414&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-526 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524365_182_20141020_ny_cima_rosso_099_cp.jpg" alt="&quot;Sick Child&quot; in wax and plaster." width="580" height="414" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-526" class="wp-caption-text">“Sick Child” in wax and plaster.</figcaption></figure>
<p> </p>
<figure id="attachment_525" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-525" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="525" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp.jpg?fit=6048%2C4320&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4320" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413822319&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141020_NY_CIMA_Rosso_111_CP" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;“Sick Child” in wax and plaster.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp.jpg?fit=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp.jpg?fit=580%2C414&amp;ssl=1" class="size-medium wp-image-525 jetpack-lazy-image" alt="&quot;Sick Child&quot; in wax and plaster." width="300" height="214" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="525" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp.jpg?fit=6048%2C4320&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4320" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413822319&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141020_NY_CIMA_Rosso_111_CP" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;“Sick Child” in wax and plaster.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp.jpg?fit=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp.jpg?fit=580%2C414&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-525" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524369_815_20141020_ny_cima_rosso_111_cp.jpg" alt="&quot;Sick Child&quot; in wax and plaster." width="300" height="214" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-525" class="wp-caption-text">“Sick Child” in wax and plaster.</figcaption></figure>
<p>For visitors relatively unfamiliar with Rosso the exhibition is filled with revelations, from near-abstract graphic works to an early experiment in photomontage. There is the shock of <em>Conversation </em>(1903), a plaster that just barely suggests human forms, while achieving an almost Rococo effect in its play of whispers and glances. Its baroque modeling, in which the figures rise out of a writhing bed of plaster, anticipates Lucio Fontana’s plasters and ceramics by decades. In the kitchen, a new series of prints from old negatives show Rosso exhibiting at the 1900 Exposition Universelle and the 1904 Salon d’Automne in the company of such modern masters as Cezanne. Richly detailed images of his Paris atelier round out the collection.</p>
<p>It is rare to see a show whose content and presentation – so thrilling yet so humble – complement each other as well as they do here. A broad passageway, in which many of the photographs are displayed, links the main exhibition space with two smaller galleries. The photographs invigorate our experience of the sculptures and drawings and unite the space by showing us the work through Rosso’s eyes. The rooms are not subdivided by genre, medium or date, and thus display a body of work that feels holistic while never becoming predictable. Without bombastic wall text and overblown claims, CIMA allows the work to speak for itself. Its insights unfold quietly, deliberately, as gradual as sunlight that slowly shades from afternoon to evening.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="527" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp.jpg?fit=6048%2C4320&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4320" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413816267&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141020_NY_CIMA_Rosso_018final_CP" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp.jpg?fit=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp.jpg?fit=580%2C414&amp;ssl=1" class="alignright wp-image-527 size-large jetpack-lazy-image" alt="20141020_NY_CIMA_Rosso_018final_CP" width="580" height="414" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="527" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/13/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp.jpg?fit=6048%2C4320&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6048,4320" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Walter Smalling Jr.&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  -- Photograph by Walter Smalling.&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1413816267&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 2014 Walter Smalling Jr. - All Rights Reserved&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20141020_NY_CIMA_Rosso_018final_CP" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The Center for Italian Modern Art (CIMA) displays an installation of sculpture, drawing, and experimental photography by modernist Medardo Rosso October 20, 2014 in New York, NY.  — Photograph by Walter Smalling.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp.jpg?fit=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp.jpg?fit=580%2C414&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-527 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524371_91_20141020_ny_cima_rosso_018final_cp.jpg" alt="20141020_NY_CIMA_Rosso_018final_CP" width="580" height="414" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em><a href="http://www.italianmodernart.org/current-exhibition/">Medardo Rosso</a>, at the Center for Italian Modern Art in New York City, can be viewed by appointment on Fridays and Saturdays. It runs through June 27.</em></p>
<p><em>Jeremy Bleeke studies twentieth-century art with a particular focus on European modernism and post-modernism. He received his MPhil in History of Art from the University of Cambridge in 2014. </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/medardo-rossos-casts-copies-and-prints-illuminating-the-artists-process/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Personal Philology &#8211; JHI Blog</title>
		<link>/personal-philology-jhi-blog/</link>
					<comments>/personal-philology-jhi-blog/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 12:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/personal-philology-jhi-blog/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[by guest contributor Richard Calis For those who care to look closely enough, the world of early modern philology has many treats in store. Contrary to its... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><em>by guest contributor Richard Calis</em></p>
<p>For those who care to look closely enough, the world of early modern philology has many treats in store. Contrary to its <a href="http://www.newcriterion.com/articles.cfm/A-kingdom-in-splinters-8106">reputation as nit-picking, dull scholarship</a>, philology is in fact a discipline full of love, strife, passion and emotion. One such passionate and dedicated, yet now sadly unknown practitioner was Pieter Fontein (1708-1788). A student of the renowned Dutch philologist Tiberius Hemsterhuis in Leiden, Fontein became a teacher at the Mennonite Church in Amsterdam in 1739 and would remain so until his death some fifty years later. Over his career, Fontein amassed an impressive collection of Latin and Greek classics, all of which he bequeathed to his church, except for a small group of related books on the Greek philosopher Theophrastus. It is this collection of forty-three <em>Theophrastiana</em> (currently in the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam) that brings back to life the philological achievements of a scholar who never made it into the annals of classical philology.</p>
<figure id="attachment_484" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-484" style="width: 191px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="484" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/06/personal-philology/photo-1-frontispiece-casaubon/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-1-frontispiece-casaubon.jpg?fit=2352%2C3695&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2352,3695" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 1 – frontispiece Casaubon" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Casaubon’s annotated copy of Theophrastus. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D17.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-1-frontispiece-casaubon.jpg?fit=191%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-1-frontispiece-casaubon.jpg?fit=580%2C911&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-484 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524331_266_photo-1-frontispiece-casaubon.jpg" alt="Casaubon's annotated copy of Theophrastus. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D17." width="191" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-484" class="wp-caption-text">Casaubon’s annotated copy of Theophrastus. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D17.</figcaption></figure>
<p>It is still unclear when exactly Fontein amassed his books, but our story begins in 1754, when he was spending his days reading a rather special book from the collection of the then-famous botanist and Professor of Anatomy Willem Röell (1700-1775). The book that Fontein found so absorbing was a 1542 edition of Theophrastus’<em> Opera Omnia</em>, printed at the famous Froben press in Basel. Moreover, the book was nothing less than a <a href="http://abo.annotatedbooksonline.com/#binding-93-9">working copy</a> of that great Theophrastus scholar Isaac Casaubon (1559-1614), who, over a century earlier, had adorned its pages with numerous notes and annotations.</p>
<p>In 1591, Casaubon had published his own edition of Theophrastus’ <em>Characteres, </em>a lively set of character sketches known for its problematic text and manuscript transmission yet also the philosopher’s most popular work. Ever since, Casaubon was known to the world of scholarship as the single most important authority on Theophrastus, a reputation that was not lost on Fontein. In fact, the primary reason that Fontein took an interest in Röell’s book was <a href="http://abo.annotatedbooksonline.com/#binding-96-7">because of Casaubon’s marginal notes</a>. This, at least, is suggested by the way in which Fontein treated them: when he went to examine the book, Fontein bought and brought with him his own clean copy of the same 1541 edition —no mean feat more than two centuries after its publication— and herein <a href="http://abo.annotatedbooksonline.com/#binding-96-169">copied nearly every single annotation</a> that Casaubon had left in his book. For pages on end, Fontein faithfully transcribed Casaubon’s notes in his own beautifully regular eighteenth-century hand.</p>
<figure id="attachment_485" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-485" style="width: 176px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img data-attachment-id="485" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/06/personal-philology/photo-2-casaubon-147/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-casaubon-147.jpg?fit=2167%2C3688&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2167,3688" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 2 – Casaubon 147" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Casaubon’s notes. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D17.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-casaubon-147.jpg?fit=176%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-casaubon-147.jpg?fit=580%2C987&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-485 size-medium jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Casaubon's notes. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D17." width="176" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/photo-2-casaubon-147.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="485" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/06/personal-philology/photo-2-casaubon-147/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-casaubon-147.jpg?fit=2167%2C3688&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2167,3688" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 2 – Casaubon 147" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Casaubon’s notes. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D17.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-casaubon-147.jpg?fit=176%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-casaubon-147.jpg?fit=580%2C987&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-485 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524332_562_photo-2-casaubon-147.jpg" alt="Casaubon's notes. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D17." width="176" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-485" class="wp-caption-text">Casaubon’s marginal notes. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D17.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_486" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-486" style="width: 174px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="486" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/06/personal-philology/photo-2-fontein-147/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-fontein-147.jpg?fit=2146%2C3696&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2146,3696" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 2 -Fontein 147" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Fontein’s transcription of Casaubon’s notes. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D19.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-fontein-147.jpg?fit=174%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-fontein-147.jpg?fit=580%2C999&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-486 size-medium jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Fontein's transcription of Casaubon's notes. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D19." width="174" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/photo-2-fontein-147.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="486" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/06/personal-philology/photo-2-fontein-147/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-fontein-147.jpg?fit=2146%2C3696&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2146,3696" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 2 -Fontein 147" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Fontein’s transcription of Casaubon’s notes. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D19.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-fontein-147.jpg?fit=174%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-2-fontein-147.jpg?fit=580%2C999&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-486 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524335_872_photo-2-fontein-147.jpg" alt="Fontein's transcription of Casaubon's notes. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D19." width="174" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-486" class="wp-caption-text">Fontein’s transcription of Casaubon’s annotations. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM: Hs VII D19.</figcaption></figure>
<p>We may pause for a moment to appreciate the great intimacy of this —to my knowledge— unique practice of relocating marginalia from an annotated copy to a pristine one. To Fontein, these were not only notes explicating a text, but also the material evidence of the reading and annotating practice of one of his greatest predecessors. We know of scholars who organized their information in <a href="https://books.google.co.uk/books?id=uEQJtGFtbKsC&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=too+much+to+know+commonplace+books&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=FR4gVcHdAsrxaODPgdgF&amp;ved=0CCoQ6AEwAg#v=onepage&amp;q=commonplace%20books&amp;f=false">commonplace books</a> but buying a two hundred year old edition to copy notes in was not everyday practice; not even for Fontein, whose book collection does not seem to include any other such inscribed copies. It will come as little surprise then that Fontein would even go on to buy Röell’s book in 1767, when the latter found himself in rough financial waters. After all, a transcription of Casaubon’s annotations was surely no replacement for the original.</p>
<p>By then, Fontein had steadily collected more and more Theophrastus editions dating from the fifteenth to the eighteenth centuries. Some of them were densely annotated. This collecting spree was undoubtedly aimed at gathering every bit of information on Theophrastus that was available. As another copy from his library attests, Fontein was concurrently working on his own edition of the <em>Characteres</em>, Originally, he drafted his material in a small, handy octavo reprint of Casaubon’s edition, published in Cambridge in 1712. Yet today it can hardly be recognized as such: the edition is now completely interleaved with huge folio-sized pages, all of them awash with Fontein’s corrections, notes and interpretations. From these ‘additions’, one can observe how he continuously reworked the text. Fontein crossed out sentences, rewrote entire paragraphs, emended or explicated words, and crammed new notes in the margins of the margins. There are at least four drafted introductions to the work and its author, some <em>prolegomena </em>and countless comments and notes on the Greek;<em> horror vacui</em> takes on a whole new meaning.</p>
<figure id="attachment_487" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-487" style="width: 620px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="487" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/06/personal-philology/photo-3-working-notes-fontein/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-3-working-notes-fontein.jpg?fit=2448%2C2448&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2448,2448" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;2.2&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 5s&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1427117792&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.15&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;50&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.03030303030303&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 3 – Working notes Fontein" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Fontein’s working notes on Theophrastus. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM Hs. XVI A5.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-3-working-notes-fontein.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-3-working-notes-fontein.jpg?fit=580%2C580&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-487 size-large jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Fontein's working notes on Theophrastus. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM Hs. XVI A5." width="580" height="580" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/photo-3-working-notes-fontein.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="487" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/06/personal-philology/photo-3-working-notes-fontein/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-3-working-notes-fontein.jpg?fit=2448%2C2448&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2448,2448" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;2.2&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 5s&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1427117792&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.15&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;50&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.03030303030303&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 3 – Working notes Fontein" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Fontein’s working notes on Theophrastus. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM Hs. XVI A5.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-3-working-notes-fontein.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/photo-3-working-notes-fontein.jpg?fit=580%2C580&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-487 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524339_95_photo-3-working-notes-fontein.jpg" alt="Fontein's working notes on Theophrastus. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM Hs. XVI A5." width="580" height="580" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-487" class="wp-caption-text">Fontein’s working notes on Theophrastus. By permission of the Special Collections of the University of Amsterdam. Shelf mark: OTM Hs. XVI A5.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Sadly, the project came to nothing, as Fontein died before its completion. But even in his final days, the philologist’s passion for the project burned steadily. In his will —made in 1769, specified in 1775, and now in the Amsterdam City Archives— Fontein gifted all his books to the Mennonite Church with the sole exception of the <em>Theophrastiana</em>, which he wanted to keep to himself. We can almost see how the elderly Fontein with only a handful of necessary books unceasingly fine-tuned his views on a notoriously elusive text, while continuously adding new material to his already massive commentary. Again and again he kept revising, never gave up, and continually worked on a more accurate edition, with Theophrastus on his mind and his cherished Casaubon on his desk. What a character he was.</p>
<p><em>Richard Calis </em><em>is a first-year Ph.D. student in history at Princeton University. He has worked for <a href="http://www.annotatedbooksonline.com/">Annotated Books Online</a> (ABO)—which provides online access to three of Fontein’s books— and is predominantly interested in book history, marginalia, news, and the various cultures of the Medieval and Early Modern Mediterranean. </em></p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/personal-philology-jhi-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commercializing Opera through Paris’ First Musical Periodical</title>
		<link>/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/</link>
					<comments>/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 03:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By guest contributor Saraswathi Shukla The first periodical to successfully distribute musical scores to the French public was founded in 1762 and continued under different names by... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><em>By guest contributor Saraswathi Shukla</em></p>
<p>The first periodical to successfully distribute musical scores to the French public was founded in 1762 and continued under different names by different editors through the French Revolution (Bruce Gustafson and David Fuller, <a href="http://ukcatalogue.oup.com/product/9780193152564.do"><em>A Catalogue of French Harpsichord Music: 1699-1780</em></a>, 1990, 17-19). In its first ten years, it ran as the <em>Journal de Clavecin</em>, offering its public “harpsichord pieces composed on ariettes and airs selected from <em>intermèdes </em>and <em>opéras comiques </em>which have had the greatest success.” <em>Opéras comiques</em> were comic Italianate operas with spoken dialogue produced at the <a href="mailto:http://www.opera-comique.com/en/timeline-opera-comique">Opéra Comique</a> in Paris.</p>
<figure id="attachment_590" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-590" style="width: 392px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="590" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/27/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/clavecin3/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/clavecin3.jpeg?fit=1378%2C1054&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1378,1054" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="clavecin3" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Journal de Clavecin&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/clavecin3.jpeg?fit=300%2C229&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/clavecin3.jpeg?fit=580%2C444&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-590" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524419_364_clavecin3.jpeg" alt="Journal de Clavecin" width="392" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-590" class="wp-caption-text">Journal de Clavecin</figcaption></figure>
<p>The publication initially consisted of harpsichord arrangements of individual opera airs grouped into “suites” of three or four on a monthly basis. The premise of the <em>Journal </em>was unprecedented and risky given the failure of other ventures in the aftermath of the Querelle des bouffons, the debate over French and Italian operatic styles that dominated the 1750s. Its success can be attributed to the shrewd marketing strategies of its editor, Charles-François Clément.</p>
<p>Clément ensured that its presentation and contents were consistently of a high quality even as other competitive periodicals emerged in its wake. Madame Leclair, a leading engraver of the day, prepared the plates, and the issues, distributed by Le Menu, were printed monthly but paginated continuously so that a single year’s issues collectively comprised 60-70 pages. (That said, no set of issues was ever bound, to my knowledge.)</p>
<figure id="attachment_588" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-588" style="width: 213px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img data-attachment-id="588" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/27/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/clavecin2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/clavecin2.jpeg?fit=510%2C789&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="510,789" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="clavecin2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Ornament table from Jean-Philipe Rameau’s Pièces de clavecin (1724)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/clavecin2.jpeg?fit=194%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/clavecin2.jpeg?fit=510%2C789&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-588 jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Ornament table from Jean-Philipe Rameau's Pièces de clavecin (1724)" width="213" height="329" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/clavecin2.jpeg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="588" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/27/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/clavecin2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/clavecin2.jpeg?fit=510%2C789&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="510,789" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="clavecin2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Ornament table from Jean-Philipe Rameau’s Pièces de clavecin (1724)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/clavecin2.jpeg?fit=194%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/clavecin2.jpeg?fit=510%2C789&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-588" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524420_938_clavecin2.jpeg" alt="Ornament table from Jean-Philipe Rameau's Pièces de clavecin (1724)" width="213" height="329" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-588" class="wp-caption-text">Ornament table from Jean-Philippe Rameau’s Pièces de clavecin (1724)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Aligning himself with the conservative harpsichord traditions of Paris may have enabled Clément to explore recent Italian musical developments without alienating factions of musical society. He embraced idiomatic French harpsichord style and ornamentation, and he adopted the typically French custom of grouping pieces into suites. Until the early 1770s, each issue consisted of two suites composed of airs from different operas instead of the traditional dance movements.</p>
<p>At the same time, Clément used both French and Italian tempo markings and combined airs by French and Italian composers in his suites. He sometimes labeled the left and right hands “G” (<em>gauche</em>) and “D” (<em>droite</em>) to clarify ambiguities about the division of music between the hands, a nomenclature first used in France by Domenico Scarlatti in his Italianate harpsichord sonatas (Jean Duron, “La recepción de la obra de Domenico Scarlatti en Francia,” <a href="mailto:https://www.casadevelazquez.org/es/publicaciones/libreria-en-linea/libro/sevilla-y-corte/"><em>Sevilla y corte: las artes y el lustro real (1729-1733)</em></a><em>, </em>2010, 313-328)<strong>. </strong>Even the physical layout of the <em>Journal</em> was associated with Italianness in the public eye: Rousseau described landscape staff paper as “Italian” in the <em>Dictionnaire de Musique </em>(Jean-Jacques Rousseau, <a href="mailto:https://archive.org/details/dictionnairedemu01rous"><em>Dictionnaire de musique</em></a>, 1772, 199-206).</p>
<figure id="attachment_584" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-584" style="width: 287px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img data-attachment-id="584" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/27/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm.png?fit=492%2C514&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="492,514" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2015-04-27 at 4.08.59 PM" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;From Le Maistre de Clavecin (Paris: 1753). Digitized by IMSLP.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm.png?fit=287%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm.png?fit=492%2C514&amp;ssl=1" class="wp-image-584 size-medium jetpack-lazy-image" alt="From Le Maistre de Clavecin (Paris: 1753). Digitized by IMSLP." width="287" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm.png" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="584" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/27/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm.png?fit=492%2C514&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="492,514" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2015-04-27 at 4.08.59 PM" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;From Le Maistre de Clavecin (Paris: 1753). Digitized by IMSLP.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm.png?fit=287%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm.png?fit=492%2C514&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-584 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524422_489_screen-shot-2015-04-27-at-4-08-59-pm.png" alt="From Le Maistre de Clavecin (Paris: 1753). Digitized by IMSLP." width="287" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-584" class="wp-caption-text">Playing music for harpsichord with violin accompaniment, not unlike the pieces in the Journal de Clavecin. From Le Maitre de Clavecin (Paris: 1753). Digitized by IMSLP.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Although the transcriptions were intended primarily as solo harpsichord pieces, flexibility of instrumentation widened the publication’s appeal to a broader range of instrumentalists. On the title page of the first print run in 1762, Clément wrote, “These pieces include the accompaniment to their airs. They can be played on harp.” The following year, he added that they could be played <em>ad libitum</em> by harpsichord and violin (the violin played the highest notes). As the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortepiano">fortepiano</a> gained popularity, Clément ensured that his arrangements remained compatible with both fortepiano and harpsichord: dynamics in the keyboard parts are limited to <em>forte </em>and <em>piano </em>while the violin parts feature more gradations.</p>
<p>Perhaps the key to Clément’s success was his ability to adapt to changes in musical style. The operas of André-Ernest-Modeste Grétry and his contemporaries prompted several musical and logistical changes in the <em>Journal.</em> The <em>Journal </em>had always presented isolated opera airs without text or context, but in its last years, it included complete vocal parts with obbligato violin and a figured bass line, representing a decisive shift away from solo keyboard repertoire. As the scores became more suitable for chamber performances of opera airs, Clément’s replaced his ariette-based suites with entire operatic scenes. Beginning in 1765, the groupings of pieces began to loosely resemble the Classical sonata, and in 1767, Clément abandoned the term “suite” entirely and stopped grouping his excerpts at all. The increasing length of each pieces probably prompted the replacement of the monthly publication of the <em>Journal </em>by an annual volume sometime between 1768 ad 1770.</p>
<p>These changes are broadly consistent with what we know of the shifts in musical aesthetics that took place soon after the arrival of Christoph Willibald Gluck in Paris in 1774 (James Johnson, <a href="mailto:http://www.ucpress.edu/book.php%3Fisbn=9780520206489"><em>Listening in Paris: A Cultural History</em></a>, 1995). Could we trace parallels between the selection of “the most successful airs” printed by the <em>Journal </em>and the new operatic tastes of the Parisian public? Unfortunately, the shift from suite to sonata, the increasing length and changing structure of musical excerpts, the attempt to capture orchestral sound, and the inclusion of text to provide dramatic narrative predate Gluck’s arrival and influence in France. Moreover, the turnaround time between the premieres of <em>opéras comiques </em>and Clément’s publications often left little time for public feedback. The <em>Journal</em> appears not to have been printing “the most successful” works, as its title page claimed, but rather the <em>newest </em>works of the Opéra-Comique. So what attracted buyers to Clément’s untested musical excerpts?</p>
<p>One possibility sees the <em>Journal</em> as part of an Enlightenment project in intellectual and cultural democratization. Clément’s uncle, the Abbé Clément, was known for his commentaries on contemporary music and co-wrote the three-volume <a href="mailto:https://archive.org/details/anecdotesdramat04portgoog"><em>Anecdotes dramatiques</em></a><em>, </em>containing “histories” about the creation and production of French <em>spectacles </em>from its “origins” (Jean-Baptiste Lully under Louis XIV) to the present (1774). The series, the elder Clément hoped, would offer something to everyone: amateurs of opera, men of letters, women, foreigners, young people. This was a project to familiarize a new class of amateurs with the cultural currency of Parisian <em>spectacles </em>(Clément, i-iv).</p>
<figure id="attachment_592" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-592" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img data-attachment-id="592" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/27/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/f2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/f2.jpeg?fit=1349%2C1054&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1349,1054" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="f2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Ariette from the Journal de Clavecin, 1768. Gallica.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/f2.jpeg?fit=300%2C234&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/f2.jpeg?fit=580%2C453&amp;ssl=1" class="size-medium wp-image-592 jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Ariette from the Journal de Clavecin, 1768. Gallica." width="300" height="234" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/f2.jpeg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="592" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/04/27/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/f2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/f2.jpeg?fit=1349%2C1054&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1349,1054" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="f2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Ariette from the Journal de Clavecin, 1768. Gallica.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/f2.jpeg?fit=300%2C234&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/f2.jpeg?fit=580%2C453&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-592" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524424_473_f2.jpeg" alt="Ariette from the Journal de Clavecin, 1768. Gallica." width="300" height="234" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-592" class="wp-caption-text">Ariette from the Journal de Clavecin, 1768. Gallica.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Unlike the <em>Anecdotes dramatiques, </em>the <em>Journal </em>did not purport to teach everything about the “most popular opera airs.” The periodical was inaccessible without a musical instrument and without knowing how to read music. Still, its dedication to a <em>fermier général, </em>composer, and future author of <a href="mailto:http://gallica.bnf.fr/ark:/12148/bpt6k503782h.r"><em>L’Essai sur la musique ancienne et moderne</em></a> (1780), Jean-Benjamin de Laborde, should not be taken lightly. Opera transcriptions enabled amateur musicians to engage closely with opera in ways that were impossible at the theater.</p>
<p>Periodicals like the <em>Journal </em>became viable business ventures around the time catalogues of <em>spectacles </em>circulated among amateur musicians and music lovers. Opportunities abounded in the 1770s for the musically inclined to build entire careers, not on performing transcriptions, but on preparing arrangements. By aiding in the formation of a new métier of commercial opera arranging, Clément handed cultural capital that had once been prized among a musical elite to amateurs and buyers of cheap music prints.</p>
<p><em>The following sound examples of ariettes from the</em> Journal de Clavecin<em> were recorded by the author:</em></p>
<p><iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Fplaylists%2F102307346&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;visual=true&amp;show_comments=true&amp;color=false&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false"></iframe></p>
<p><em><a href="https://berkeley.academia.edu/SaraswathiShukla">Saraswathi Shukla</a> is a second-year graduate student in the Music Department at UC Berkeley. She draws on her undergraduate training in history to research the instrumental music and musical culture of 17th- and 18th-centuries France and Germany. Her research often examines the circulation of music across genres and social, geographic, and temporal boundaries.</em></p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/commercializing-opera-through-paris-first-musical-periodical/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Out of chaos, some sort of order: The International Congress on Medieval Studies at 50, May 14-17, 2015</title>
		<link>/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/</link>
					<comments>/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Baby Devi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 09:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[by guest contributor Elizabeth Biggs The International Congress on Medieval Studies held in Kalamazoo last week was immensely diverse, given its 3,000 attendees, but a good reflection... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><em>by guest contributor Elizabeth Biggs</em></p>
<p>The International Congress on Medieval Studies held in Kalamazoo last week was immensely diverse, given its 3,000 attendees, but a good reflection of medievalists generally. It didn’t take itself particularly seriously, the alcohol flowed generously, and a good book or argument was warmly welcomed. It was the fiftieth birthday of the conference, as well as other major anniversaries such as 600 years since the Battle of Agincourt and 750 years since the first acknowledged Parliament.<noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="700" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/05/25/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/agincourt/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/agincourt.jpg?fit=3501%2C2333&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3501,2333" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;2.9&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Fujifilm A170 A180&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1271470705&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;5.7&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;200&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.022222222222222&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Agincourt" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/agincourt.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/agincourt.jpg?fit=580%2C387&amp;ssl=1" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-700" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524482_996_agincourt.jpg" alt="Agincourt" width="300" height="200" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript> Everyone was there to have a good time, hear excellent papers and meet old and new friends. Every evening ended with multiple wine receptions, often with an open bar, sponsored by publishers, universities or learned societies. The book exhibit was equally generous, with huge numbers of publishers, secondhand book dealers, and manuscript dealers swarmed by eager delegates. Perhaps the most popular session of all was that of the Pseudo Society on Saturday evening, when a lecture hall was filled to bursting with medievalists there to hear about how IKEA is a secret society where Viking survivors are hiding, among other papers that toyed with academic norms for laughs as well as making a serious point about the absurdities of being an academic.</p>
<figure id="attachment_701" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-701" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img data-attachment-id="701" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/05/25/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/henj/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/henj.jpg?fit=500%2C349&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,349" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Henj" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Some speculations about the true nature of IKEA.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/henj.jpg?fit=300%2C209&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/henj.jpg?fit=500%2C349&amp;ssl=1" class="size-medium wp-image-701 jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Some speculations about the true nature of IKEA." width="300" height="209" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/henj.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="701" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/05/25/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/henj/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/henj.jpg?fit=500%2C349&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,349" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Henj" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Some speculations about the true nature of IKEA.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/henj.jpg?fit=300%2C209&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/henj.jpg?fit=500%2C349&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-701" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524482_610_henj.jpg" alt="Some speculations about the true nature of IKEA." width="300" height="209" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-701" class="wp-caption-text">Some speculations about the true nature of IKEA.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Medieval history has certainly changed and grown in the last fifty years. The dizzying array of topics in medieval studies that were included in the thick program ranged from experimental archaeology using ballistics gel to gauge the effects of different arrows on different types of armor, to digital humanities efforts to edit texts online and the <a href="https://www.englandsimmigrants.com/">England’s Immigrants project database</a>. None of these topics would have been conceivable at the first major conference at Kalamazoo in 1964, when the cost was just $5, and there were five parallel sessions in a two-day event rather than the current just under fifty parallel sessions across three and a half days. Even then, the conference was already self-consciously interdisciplinary. It featured theology, liturgy, philosophy, history, and English literature, although in separate disciplinary sessions. All of those themes were still present this year, even if they are now often couched in different language. Liturgy is as likely to be discussed in terms of space and ritual as in terms of the books used by nuns. The study of how other periods conceptualized the idea of the “medieval” has hearteningly become popular, and illuminates both our understanding of the term “medieval” and the later periods under consideration. Kalamazoo now also is doing useful work in thinking about the changing state of the profession in the age of adjunct teaching. There were sessions on being a medievalist in a small college where no one else does what you do, on the possibilities of alt-ac careers of all types, and on how best to teach medieval topics in diverse settings. All of this was an important reminder that being a scholar is wider than research, and that teaching and working outside the ivory tower are vital parts of medievalists’ experiences.</p>
<p>The sessions I ultimately chose to go to were all fascinating and made me think in new ways about the work I’m doing. The sheer size of the conference meant that I created, in effect, a mini-conference of late-medieval English history, with a side jaunt to medicine and canon law, to pick up some of the ways in which scholars are thinking about these issues. I went to a session on Magic and Medicine in which <a href="https://www.utoledo.edu/llss/history/faculty/GeamanK.html">Kristen Geaman</a> looked at a court case that I’ve been trying to write about for my own thesis, the 1441 treason and witchcraft trial of Eleanor Cobham, through the lens of medieval infertility treatments.</p>
<figure id="attachment_703" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-703" style="width: 291px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img data-attachment-id="703" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/05/25/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/humphrey__eleanor/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/humphrey__eleanor.jpg?fit=523%2C540&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="523,540" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Humphrey_&amp;amp;_Eleanor" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Humphrey and Eleanor Cobham.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/humphrey__eleanor.jpg?fit=291%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/humphrey__eleanor.jpg?fit=523%2C540&amp;ssl=1" class="size-medium wp-image-703 jetpack-lazy-image" alt="Humphrey and Eleanor Cobham." width="291" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/humphrey__eleanor.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="703" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/05/25/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/humphrey__eleanor/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/humphrey__eleanor.jpg?fit=523%2C540&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="523,540" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Humphrey_&amp;amp;_Eleanor" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Humphrey and Eleanor Cobham.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/humphrey__eleanor.jpg?fit=291%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/humphrey__eleanor.jpg?fit=523%2C540&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-703" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524483_660_humphrey__eleanor.jpg" alt="Humphrey and Eleanor Cobham." width="291" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-703" class="wp-caption-text">Humphrey and Eleanor Cobham.</figcaption></figure>
<p>She argued that we should take Eleanor at her word that she wanted a child, and so she might well have commissioned magical activity. I’d never thought before that Eleanor might actually have done more than play around with horoscopes, and have always read the court records as politically motivated, given that Eleanor’s husband was the heir presumptive to the young Henry VI and his enemies were circling. I’m glad to be able to rethink those assumptions! Even very old forms of scholarship, such as prosopography, gained new life. <a href="https://www.royalholloway.ac.uk/history/staffdirectory/personalhomepages/carolinebarron.aspx">Caroline Barron</a> on the glovers of London or <a href="www.slu.edu/center-for-digital-humanities/staff/dr-john-mcewan">John McEwan</a>’s work on the distribution of wealth in the city used older methods to assess new questions in social and economic history that often reflect the experiences of modern society: experiences of inequality, how to survive in a rapidly changing world, and how best to create supportive institutions that protected members’ careers and incomes.</p>
<p>The reason I could be there at all was thanks to a travel bursary from the Society of the White Hart, as I was speaking in their session on political power. I think they found my interdisciplinary paper—with its architectural study alongside chronicle evidence of politics in Richard II’s reign—different, but the comments and questions were unfailingly generous and helpful.</p>
<figure id="attachment_704" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-704" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img data-attachment-id="704" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/05/25/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/cloister-today/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/cloister-today.jpg?fit=3456%2C5184&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3456,5184" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;4.5&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 700D&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1378686942&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;18&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.016666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="cloister today" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;The restored St. Stephen’s Cloisters, looking west to Westminster Hall, also part of Richard’s repair work at the Palace.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/cloister-today.jpg?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/cloister-today.jpg?fit=580%2C870&amp;ssl=1" class="size-medium wp-image-704 jetpack-lazy-image" alt="The restored St. Stephen's Cloisters, looking west to Westminster Hall, also part of Richard's repair work at the Palace." width="200" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/cloister-today.jpg" /><noscript><img data-lazy-fallback="1" data-attachment-id="704" data-permalink="https://jhiblog.org/2015/05/25/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/cloister-today/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/cloister-today.jpg?fit=3456%2C5184&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3456,5184" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;4.5&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 700D&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1378686942&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;18&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.016666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="cloister today" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;The restored St. Stephen’s Cloisters, looking west to Westminster Hall, also part of Richard’s repair work at the Palace.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/cloister-today.jpg?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/jhiblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/cloister-today.jpg?fit=580%2C870&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-704" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1660524485_694_cloister-today.jpg" alt="The restored St. Stephen's Cloisters, looking west to Westminster Hall, also part of Richard's repair work at the Palace." width="200" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1"/></noscript><figcaption id="caption-attachment-704" class="wp-caption-text">The restored St. Stephen’s Cloisters, looking west to Westminster Hall, also part of Richard’s repair work at the Palace.</figcaption></figure>
<p>They left me heartened about the work that I do, looking outwards from an institution to the cultural and political world around it, rather than the general inward-looking run of institutional history. It is amazing how much it helps to know that I’m doing work that people from a range of fields think is interesting. Kalamazoo reminded me of the range of work medievalists do and the range of settings they do it in, from research universities to public engagement, to teaching colleges. It reminded me that my day job may well turn out to be outside academia entirely, but that I can still be a small part of a huge, sprawling conversation. I’ll hopefully be back next year, to drink more wine, meet more people, and continue to reflect on what it means to identify oneself as a medieval historian, whether teaching inside or outside a university.</p>
<p><i><a href="http://www.virtualststephens.org.uk/users/ecb528yorkacuk">Elizabeth Biggs</a> is a Ph.D. student in History at the University of York. She is researching Stephen’s College, Westminster, from 1348 to 1548, as part of <a href="http://www.virtualststephens.org.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a larger AHRC-funded project</a> on St Stephen’s Chapel from 1292 to the Blitz in 1941. Her work focuses on the people who worked at the college, donated money and lands to the college, or who knew it through its presence at the heart of the medieval Palace of Westminster. She can be reached on <a href="https://twitter.com/elizabethcbiggs">Twitter</a> and via email.</i></p>
<p><!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
		</div>
<p><script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/out-of-chaos-some-sort-of-order-the-international-congress-on-medieval-studies-at-50-may-14-17-2015/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
